Guide to the Beverly Coyle Papers, circa 1800-2016 (bulk 1952-2016)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Beverly Coyle Papers
circa 1800-2016
1952-2016
Coyle, Beverly
18.5 cubic feet (21 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Collection includes manuscripts, professional and personal correspondence, subject files, teaching files, publicity and press clippings. Files hold typescripts, handwritten notes and drafts, as well as academic notebooks. Family papers in the collection include correspondence, press clippings, photographs and family history files, including some genealogy documentation. Press clippings include reviews of Coyle's writings, as well as clippings regarding selected family members. Collection contains photographic prints, CDs, DVDs, as well as audio and video cassettes.
Biographical Note
Beverly Jones Coyle was born August 2, 1946, in Miami, Florida, a fifth generation Floridian, and daughter of a pastor at North Miami Beach Methodist Church. Coyle is known for her literary criticism, short stories, and novels. After receiving a B.A. from Florida State University (1968) and a Ph.D. from the University of Nebraska (1974), Beverly Coyle taught English at the University of Newcastle, Australia (1974-1976) and Vassar College, New York (1977-2002). The Kneeling Bus was Coyle's first work of fiction, and was based on family anecdotes inspired by Florida life in Boynton Beach, Fernandina Beach, Jacksonville and Venice-Nokomis.
Coyle's novels include: The Kneeling Bus (Ticknor & Fields, 1990); In Troubled Waters (Ticknor & Fields, 1993) and Taken In (Penguin Books, 1998). Dramatic works include: Parallel Lives (2009); The Smoking Gun (2008); In Our own Voice (2003). Scholarly publications include: Secretaries of the Moon: The Letters of Wallace Stevens and Jose Rodriquez Feo, co-edited with Alan Filreis, Duke University Press, 1986; An Anchorage of Thought: The Study of Aphorism in Wallace Stevens' Poetry, Ann Arbor: UMI Research Press, 1983. Additional publications include: The Pride and The Shame, Forum: The Magazine of the Florida Humanities Council, Fall/Winter 1993; Taking Martha With Me, Grand Street, Summer 1986; A Thought to be Rehearsed: Study of Aphorism in Wallace Stevens Poetry, Publications of the Modern Language Association, March 1976.
Scope and Content Note
The majority of the collection contains manuscripts and typescripts, many in draft form, including character and plot development notations handwritten by the author, as well as correspondence, both professional and personal. Writings include a collection of essays from Coyle's college years. Notebooks document Coyle's own coursework as a student during the 1960s.
Manuscript files of dramatic works contain scripts, research notes, correspondence, musical scores, and some publicity. Subject files include documentation of grant proposals, book tour logistics, and reference and research notes for works in progress. Teaching files contain handwritten notes, typescript lecture notes, and mimeographed class handouts.
Personal and professional files contain correspondence with publishers, editors, and peers. These files also contain documentation of the author's management of her writing career, including press clippings, pitch letters for works in progress, publishing contracts and general publicity logistics.
Extensive personal and family correspondence document Coyle's professional career and family history containing feedback, insights and support from family members and friends. Professional correspondence includes letters from Holly Stevens, daughter of Wallace Stevens, Meryl Streep, regarding a screenplay of In Troubled Waters, and letters from fellow writers and artists including Ann Imbrie, Ruth Eller, Daniel Pinkwater, and Kevin Cawley.
Photographic prints primarily document family history, Florida locales, and some professional documentation including publicity photography. Audio visual material also includes audio recordings of selected dramatic works, and interviews with the author.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Cawley, Kevin; Eller, Ruth; Imbrie, Ann E. (Ann Elizabeth); O'Connor, Flannery; Pinkwater, Daniel; Stevens, Holly; Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955; Streep, Meryl
Organizations:
Vassar College--Faculty; Methodist Church; University of Nebraska; University of Newcastle
Subjects:
Literature--Women Authors; Women authors, American; Women college teachers
Places:
Florida--Description and travel
Document Types:
Audiovisual materials; Audiocassettes; Clippings (information artifacts); Compact discs; Correspondence; Drafts (documents); Photographs; Printed ephemera; Scripts (documents)
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, 2019. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, August 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Beverly Coyle, 2002. [M2002-014, M2002-021]
Additional gift of Beverly Coyle, 2017. [M2017-001]
Series List
- Series I. Writings, 1952-2016
- Series II. Subject Files, 1969-2004
- Series III. Teaching Files, 1974-2000
- Series IV. Publicity, 1942-2009
- Series V. Notebooks, 1960-1982
- Series VI. Correspondence, 1960-2009
- Series VII. Biography and Family, 1936-2002
- Series VIII. Audiovisual Materials, circa 1800-2009
Container List
- Series I. Writings
  - Dramatic Works
    - A Man and a Woman and a Blackbird — play script, (TS) (Folders 1.1-1.9)
    - A Man and a Woman and a Blackbird — play scripts and workshop notes, 2000-2012 (Folders 1.10-1.16)
    - A Man and a Woman and a Blackbird — script and synopsis, 2006 (Folders 1.17-1.18)
    - Barb and Jenna: Our First Twins — scripts and notes, 2004-2016 (Folders 1.19-1.30)
    - In Our Own Voice, Stories By U.S. Female Vets, 2003-2011 (Folders 1.31-1.34)
    - Jazz Journey Into Literary Florida, 1994 (Folder 1.35)
    - Parallel Lives — research and notes, 1995 (Folders 1.36-1.38)
    - Parallel Lives — play scripts and notes, 1999-2009 (Folders 1.39-2.12)
    - Sandy Falls — screenplay, 2003 (Folders 2.13-2.18)
    - The Smoking Gun — script drafts, 2007-2008 (Folders 2.19-2.29)
    - Troubled Waters — screenplay, 1996 (Folder 2.30)
    - Untitled screenplay — draft, 1980-1981; (TS) (Folders 2.31-2.34)
    - What Boys Want — play script, 1999; (TS) (Folders 2.35-2.36)
  - Manuscripts
    - Albert Ennui's Room, (TS, MS) (Folders 3.1-3.2)
    - The Baboon Hours — draft, (TS) (Folders 3.3-3.5)
    - The Cat and the Coyote, (TS) (Folder 3.6)
    - Chapter Two: Greenleaf, the Uses of Irony, (TS) (Folder 3.7)
    - Dad's Trip, a young adult novel, 1982; (unfinished TS) (Folder 3.8)
    - Direct Dialing — draft, (TS) (Folders 3.9-3.11)
    - The Kneeling Bus — drafts, (TS) (Folders 3.12-3.36)
    - In Troubled Waters — drafts, 1991-1993; (TS) (Folders 3.37-3.49)
    - In Troubled Waters — drafts, 1991-1993; (TS) (Folders 4.1-4.51)
    - In Troubled Waters — drafts, 1991-1993; (TS) (Folders 5.1-5.50)
    - In Troubled Waters — drafts, 1991-1993; (TS) (Folders 6.1-6.19)
    - Maggie Jones, Her Daughters, Their Husbands, (TS) (Folder 6.20)
    - O, for a Thousand Tongues to Sing — drafts, (TS) (Folder 6.21)
    - One Woman Show, unrealized — drafts, (TS) (Folders 6.22-6.24)
    - Pocketbooks — drafts, (TS) (Folders 6.25-6.28)
    - Quid Sit Paroemia: A Collector's Item Erasmus' Adagia Reconsidered, 1981 (Folder 6.29)
    - Red and Yellow, Catch a Fellow — drafts, 1994; (TS) (Folders 6.30-6.31)
    - Taken In — drafts, 1993-1997; (TS) (Folders 6.32-6.46)
    - Taken In — drafts, 1993-1997; (TS) (Folders 7.1-7.45)
    - Taken In — drafts, 1993-1997; (TS) (Folders 8.1-8.43)
    - Taken In — drafts, 1993-1997; (TS) (Folders 9.1-9.8)
    - Taking Martha With Me — drafts, (TS) (Folders 9.9-9.10)
    - The Seventh Day — drafts, (TS) (Folders 9.11-9.14)
    - Sweet Week of Dying — drafts, (TS) (Folders 9.15-9.16)
    - The Square Rigger Comb, a young adult novel — drafts, original, 1981-1982; (TS) (Folders 9.17-9.22)
    - Untitled — notes, (MS) (Folder 9.23)
    - Untitled — notes, (MS, TS) (Folders 18.22-18.24)
    - Untitled, Harriet Heard the Phone…, 1977; (TS) (Folder 18.25)
    - Untitled Young Adult Novel — drafts, 1980-1982; (TS) (Folders 9.24-9.27)
  - Speeches and Essays
    - Essays (misc), poems, notations, 1965-1966 (Folder 10.1)
    - Flannery O'Connor's Revelation, 1994 Nov 1 (Folder 10.2)
    - Met Life Foundation, 1994 Feb 16 (Folder 10.3)
    - Scene, Capture, Funeral, Trail (Taken In) (Folder 10.4)
    - University of Tampa, speech, 1997 (Folder 10.5)
  - Notes
    - In Troubled Waters, character development (Folder 10.6)
    - In Troubled Waters, (with edits from Dorothy Jones) (Folder 10.7)
    - In Troubled Waters, 1990-1992 (Folder 10.8)
    - Kneeling Bus (Folder 10.9)
    - Fragments, 1990 (Folder 10.10)
    - Taken In (Folder 10.11)
    - Taken In, 2004; (notebook) (Folder 10.12)
    - Talk at Grandfather's Funeral, 1991 (Folder 10.13)
  - Student work
    - PhD dissertation — An Anchorage of Thought: The Study of Aphorism In Wallace Stevens' Poetry, 1974 (Folders 10.16-10.17)
    - Juvenilia — Philosophy, school paper, 1963 (Folder 10.18)
    - Juvenilia — miscellaneous school work, 1952-1964 (Folder 10.19)
    - An American Dialogue, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.20)
    - Archetypal Patterns in Poetry, Maud Bodkin, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.21)
    - The Augustan Satire, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.22)
    - Basic Judaism, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.23)
    - The Boy, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.24)
    - Children and the Failure of Language in Paterson, 1970; (TS) (Folder 10.25)
    - Classification of Methodology, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.26)
    - The Comparative Study of Elements of Fiction, Melville, Twain Dreiser, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.27)
    - A Consideration of Mark Twain's The Mysterious Stranger, 1971; (TS) (Folder 10.28)
    - Doubleness of Structure On Seeing the Elgin Marbles, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.29)
    - Dramatic Structure in William Carlos Williams' Asphodel…, 1970; (TS) (Folder 10.30)
    - Dynamics of Faith, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.31)
    - The Explicit and Implicit Problem in the System and the Gospel, 1968; (TS) (Folders 10.32-10.33)
    - A Focus on University and Literary Scholarship, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.34)
    - From Classic to Romantic, the Premise of Taste in 18th Century English Literature, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.35)
    - History and Myth: The Operation of Imagery in the French Revolution, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.36)
    - The Implications of Critical Theory…, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.37)
    - It Could Have Happened to Anyone, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.38)
    - The Kingdom of God in America, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.39)
    - The Lament Formula, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.40)
    - Language, Truth and Logic, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.41)
    - Matthew Arnold as Social Critic, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.42)
    - Modern Myth in Drama, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.43)
    - The Motif of Listening in William Faulkner's Absalom, Absalom, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.44)
    - The Novels of William Faulkner, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.45)
    - Order and Disorder in The Sound and the Fury, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.46)
    - Paul Tillich: How Methodology Conveys Meaning, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.47)
    - The Possibilities of the Hip Scene, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.48)
    - The Power of Symbol in Work of Art…, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.49)
    - Protestant Catholic Jew, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.50)
    - Questions and Answers Concerning the Friar, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.51)
    - Ramifications on the Pastoral Controversy…, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.52)
    - The Religious Situation, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.53)
    - Shelley's Ode to Liberty, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.54)
    - The Stranger, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.55)
    - A Study of C.F. Strauch's Variorum Edition: Brahma, 1969; (TS) (Folder 10.56)
    - A Study of Emerson's Poetic Concerns as Revealed In His Manuscripts, 1970; (TS) (Folder 10.57)
    - The Symbolic Use of Walls, 1966; (TS) (Folder 10.58)
    - The Thematic Significance of the First in Henry James' The Ambassadors, 1971; (TS) (Folder 10.59)
    - A Theological Criticism: Heightened Self-Consciousness, 1967; (TS) (Folder 10.60)
    - To Be Inspired, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.61)
    - Two Modern Poets, 1968; (TS) (Folder 10.62)
  - Published Work
    - An Anchorage of Thought: Defining the Role of Aphorism in Wallace Stevens' Poetry, Modern Language Association of America, 1976 (Folder 10.63)
    - In Troubled Waters (excerpt), Cantilevers, FLA Southern College, 1993 (Folder 10.64)
    - The Pride and the Shame, Forum Magazine, 1993 (Folder 10.65)
    - Taking Martha With Me, Grand Street, 1986 (Folder 10.66)
  - Writings by Others
    - Cawley, Kevin, poetry (Folder 10.67)
    - Coyle, William, 1970; (TS) (Folder 10.68)
    - Eller, Ruth, poetry, 1983 (Folder 10.69)
    - Offprints - Michael Murray, Robert DeMaria, Jr., Frank Doggett, 1973-1985 (Folder 10.70)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - Doctorow, E.L. — notes (Folder 11.1)
  - O'Connor, Flannery — notes (Folder 11.2)
  - O'Connor, Flannery — children (Folders 18.10-18.12)
  - Contemporary Novelists (Folder 11.3)
  - Floating Opera (Folder 11.4)
  - Florida Vassar Club, 1990-1996 (Folder 11.5)
  - Mellon Grant Proposal, 1980-1981 (Folder 11.6)
  - Mellon Grant, Structuralist - Post Structuralist Theory, 1980 (Folder 11.7)
  - Parallel Lives — contracts, 2002-2003 (Folder 11.8)
  - Poetry, Tradition and Experiment in Poetry (Folder 11.9)
  - Poetry — University of Nebraska, 1969 (Folders 18.13-18.14)
  - Research, press clippings, 1989-1994 (Folders 11.10-11.11)
  - Song of Solomon — notes (Folder 11.12)
  - Stevens, Wallace — quotes (Folder 11.13)
  - Stevens, Wallace — research, 1985-1988 (Folders 11.14-11.16)
  - Tempest — notes (Folder 11.17)
  - Vassar — Coyle Professional Review, 1991-2004 (Folders 11.18-11.20)
  - Publishing — Book tours, 1990-1994 (Folders 11.28-11.31)
  - Publishing — Florida book tour, In Troubled Waters, 1993-1994 (Folder 11.32)
  - Publishing — Florida Vassar Club Tour, 1991 (Folder 11.33)
  - Publishing — In Troubled Waters, 1992-1996 (Folders 11.34-11.37)
  - Publishing — Taken In, 1994-2000 (Folders 11.38-11.40)
- Series III. Teaching Files
  - American Literature — Hawthorne (Folder 18.15)
  - American Literature — Renaissance, 1978 (Folder 18.16)
  - The American Short Story, 1974-1975 (Folder 11.41)
  - Bierce, Ambrose (Folder 11.42)
  - Borges, Jorge Luis, 1977 (Folder 18.17)
  - Faculty evaluations, from students, 1992-1993 (Folder 11.43)
  - Faulkner, Hamlet (Folder 11.44)
  - Faulkner's Light in August (Folder 11.45)
  - Flannery O'Connor (Folder 18.18)
  - Intro to Creative Writing, 2000 (Folder 11.46)
  - James Joyce (Folder 11.47)
  - History of American Literature — Lecture notes, 1974-1976 (Folders 18.19-18.20)
  - Martin, Jane, Voltaire, Woolf, circa 1980-1989 (Folder 12.1)
  - Poetry, notes (Folder 12.2)
  - Pound, Ezra (Folder 12.3)
  - Short Story Writing (Folders 12.4-12.5)
  - Studies in Fiction, 1979 (Folder 12.6)
  - Symbolism, Flannery O'Connor, TS, lecture (Folder 18.21)
  - Twain, Realists, American Literature (Folder 12.7)
  - University of Tampa, Kneeling Bus, 1997 (Folder 12.8)
  - Yeats, notes, handouts (Folder 12.9)
- Series IV. Publicity
  - General
    - In Troubled Waters, 1993-1996 (Folders 11.21-11.23)
    - In Troubled Waters — reading, 1993-1996 (Folder 11.24)
    - Kneeling Bus — publicity, correspondence, 1989-1995 (Folders 11.25-11.26)
    - Secretaries of the Moon, 1987-1988 (Folder 11.27)
  - Press Clippings
    - Family-related, Coyle, Jones, Lee, 1942-1988 (Folder 12.10)
    - General — Florida, 1990-1996 (Folder 12.11)
    - In Troubled Waters, 1993-1996 (Folders 12.12-12.16)
    - The Kneeling Bus, 1989-1997 (Folders 12.17-12.23)
    - Parallel Lives, staged performance, 1999-2009 (Folders 12.24-12.27)
    - Secretaries of the Moon, 1987 (Folder 12.28)
    - Taken In, 1997-1998 (Folder 12.29)
- Series V. Notebooks
  - 16th century Renaissance Poetry, circa 1960-1969 (Folder 12.30)
  - 19th century American Novel, circa 1960-1969 (Folder 12.31)
  - 20th century Poetry, circa 1960-1969 (Folder 12.32)
  - American Literature Since 1914, circa 1960-1969 (Folder 12.33)
  - Romanticism, circa 1960-1979 (Folders 12.34-12.35)
  - Travel journals, 1976-1982 (Folder 12.36)
  - Vassar, circa 1970-1979 (Folders 12.37-12.39)
- Series VI. Correspondence
  - Academic — Incoming
    - University of Nebraska, staff, 1970-1979 (Folder 13.1)
    - University of Newcastle, staff, 1975- 1977 (Folder 13.2)
    - Fergusson, Fran - Vassar President, 1990-1995 (Folder 13.3)
    - Vassar Mellon Grant, seminar, 1980-1982 (Folder 13.4)
    - Vassar Tenure Review, 1984-1995 (Folders 13.5-13.6)
  - Professional — Incoming
    - General, 1991-1997 (Folders 13.8-13.10)
    - A Man a Woman and a Blackbird, 2007-2008 (Folder 13.7)
    - Congratulatory, Kneeling Bus, In Troubled Waters, 1993-1994 (Folder 13.11)
    - Kneeling Bus, 1987-1994 (Folders 13.12-13.14)
    - Parallel Lives, 2002-2004 (Folders 13.15-13.17)
    - The Smoking Gun, emails, notes, 2009 (Folder 13.18)
  - Publishing — Incoming
    - General, 1983-2005 (Folders 13.19-13.23)
    - General, 1983-2005 (Folder 18.3)
    - Modern Language Association of America, 1974-1975 (Folder 13.24)
  - Persons of Note — Incoming
    - Atkins, Dorothy, 1978 (Folder 13.25)
    - Boyd, David, 1974-1979 (Folders 18.4-18.5)
    - Buttel, Robert, 1973-1976 (Folder 13.2)
    - Cavanaugh, Hilayne, 1977-1978 (Folder 13.27)
    - Cawley, Kevin, 1982-1986 (Folders 13.28-13.29)
    - Coyle, Bill, 1975-1979 (Folder 13.30)
    - Dye, Nancy, 1993-1994 (Folder 13.31)
    - Eller, Ruth, 1978-1982 (Folders 13.32-13.33)
    - Gunew, Sneja, 1977-1982 (Folder 13.34)
    - Imbrie, Ann, 1982-1993 (Folders 13.35, 18.6)
    - King, Noel, 1975-1978 (Folders 18.8, 13.39)
    - Mallon, Thomas, 1980-1989 (Folders 13.36-13.38)
    - Litz, Prof. A. Walton, 1973-1977 (Folder 13.40)
    - Lyon, Melvin, 1976-1990 (Folder 13.41)
    - Mays, Andrew, 1979-1980 (Folder 13.42)
    - O'Connor, C., 1977-1978 (Folder 13.43)
    - Owen, Charles, 1977 (Folder 13.44)
    - Pinkwater, Daniel, 1976-1983 (Folders 13.45-13.46)
    - Pinkwater, Daniel, 1976-1983 (Folder 18.9)
    - Pritchard, Stanford, 1988-1990 (Folder 13.47)
    - Roskowski, Sue, 1975-1978 (Folder 13.48)
    - Seibold, Danny, 1975-1998 (Folder 13.49)
    - Stevens, Holly, 1974-1990 (Folder 13.50)
    - Streep, Meryl, (regarding In Troubled Waters), undated (Folder 13.51)
  - General — Incoming
    - General, undated (Folders 14.1-14.3)
    - General, 1966-1976 (Folder 14.9)
    - General, 1977-1990 (Folders 14.10-14.29)
    - General, 1990-1998 (Folders 15.1-15.27)
    - General, 1999-2004 (Folders 15.31-15.32)
    - Cards and notes, 1993-1997 (Folders 14.4-14.8)
    - High school students, Brebeuf Jesuit Prep, 1998 (Folders 15.28-15.30)
  - Family and Friends — Incoming and Outgoing
    - Australia, 1974-1976 (Folder 18.2)
    - To family, 1960-2004 (Folders 16.1-16.11)
    - To Bill Coyle, circa 1970-1979 (Folder 16.12)
    - To friends and colleagues, 1976-2002 (Folders 16.13-16.15)
    - Incoming and outgoing email, 1997-2003 (Folders 16.16-16.17)
- Series VII. Biography and Family
  - Family Correspondence
    - To and from - C.S. Lee, 1966-1976 (Folders 16.18-16.19)
    - C.S. Lee — to children, grandchildren, circa 1970-1999 (Folders 16.20-16.26)
    - From - C.S. and Goldie Lee, 1975-1988 (Folders 16.27-16.30)
    - From - Dorothy Lee Jones, circa 1970-1999 (Folders 16.31-16.40)
    - From - Dorothy Lee Jones, circa 1970-1999 (Folder 18.7)
    - To - Dorothy Lee Jones, 1983-2000 (Folder 17.1)
    - From - Grandma Lee, 1974-1994 (Folder 17.2)
    - From – Laurie Jones, 1972-1998 (Folders 17.3- 17.5)
    - From - Nancy and Bob Temple, 1975-1979 (Folder 17.6)
  - Jones Family
    - Dorothy May Lee — academic records, 1936-1939 (Folder 17.7)
    - Laurie Jones — academic records, 1967-1977 (Folder 17.8)
    - Nancy Jones — academic records, 1949-1958 (Folder 17.9)
    - Bible Quiz Game (Folder 18.1)
    - John Louis Jones — calendar/journal, 1969 (Folder 17.10)
    - Church records — Beverly, Laurie, Dorothy and Nancy, 1944-1964 (Folder 17.11)
    - Family documents, including John Louis Jones ID Card, 1957 (Folder 17.15)
    - Velma Jones Royal — correspondence, 1944-1968 (Folder 17.16)
  - Lee Family
    - Florida land, deed maps, 1988-1990 (Folder 17.12)
    - Lee Family History, compiled by Thelma Lee Clonts, 1991 (Folder 17.1)
    - Lee Family Tree, 1987 (Folder 17.14)
    - Certificates — Charles and Goldie Lee, 1952-1967 (Folder 17.17)
    - Family History, 1991-2001 (Folders 17.18-17.19)
    - Lee, Charles — Lee Family Genealogy, 1962-2002 (Folders 17.20-17.22)
    - C.S. Lee — rust fund documentation, 1943 (Folder 17.23)
  - Beverly Coyle
    - Certificates, report cards, 1956-2001 (Folders 15.33, 18.26)
    - High school yearbook, Fernandina Beach High School, 1964 (Folder 15.34)
- Series VIII. Audiovisual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Beverly Coyle, circa 1950-1969 (Folder 19.1)
    - Beverly Coyle — publicity photos, circa 1970-1999 (Folder 19.2)
    - Children — Lee and Jones family, circa 1910-1969 (Folder 19.3)
    - Eller, Ruth, circa 1940-1979 (Folder 19.4)
    - Jones Family, circa 1930-2009 (Folder 19.5)
    - Lee Family, circa 1920-1939 (Folder 19.6)
    - Family portraiture, circa 1800-1959 (Folder 19.7)
    - Family group portraiture, circa 1800-1969 (Folder 19.8)
    - Family wedding photos, circa 1910s-1979 (Folder 19.9)
    - Military, circa 1920-1949 (Folders 19.10-19.11)
    - Daniel Pinkwater, circa 1980-1989 (Folder 20.1)
    - Residences, locations, circa 1910-1949 (Folder 20.2)
    - Scrapbooks, Coyle wedding, 1970 (Folder 20.3)
    - Unidentified, 1911-1999 (Folders 20.4-20.8)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - In Troubled Waters, undated (Box 21)
    - Letty Progrebin and Beverly Coyle, 1996; (120-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Polly Holliday at Vassar, 1994 May 9; (2 cassettes) (Box 21)
    - Bill's Father, Uncle Joe, 2003 Feb-Mar; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Revelation, Connie, Leslie, Bev, Bill, etc., 2003 Dec 5; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - In Troubled Waters — play for radio, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Price to White (by Bill), 2nd session Pinehill, 2003 Mar; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Sanders Auditorium, [Vassar College], 1990Feb 14 (Box 21)
    - Saved (phone?) messages, Polly Holliday, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Practice, undated; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Alex, 1997 Mar; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Polly Holliday (rev), undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Beverly Coyle, Brett, DMP, Paul, Vassar College, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Martha and Mary Beth, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Bev and Laurie Singing Bev's Letter, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Beverly Coyle and Editor at Viking Jane Von Melburn, 1997 May; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Untitled, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Wunderhorn, undated; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Florida Humanities Council Radio, 1994 Jun; (100-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Bev Reading, undated; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Pogrebin and Coyle, Fort Lauderdale, 1997 Mar; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - In Troubled Waters, Kim Hunter, undated (Box 21)
    - David Rothenberg Ruth Draper, 1985 Mar 28; (90-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - NPR P Lives, 2003 May 23; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Third Session, Pinewood, Bev's Job, 2003 Mar; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Scene 6 Denial and Pro Black Man, undated; (45-minute cassette) (Box 21)
    - Lisa Kron – P. Lives, undated; (60-minute cassette) (Box 21)